trendcounter.com 2001-01-19

# Privacy Policy - WebTrends Live, WebTrends Corporation

> The following information describes how we handle the information we gather about visitors to our customers' web sites as well as information about our customers' visits to our web site to retrieve their reports. 
> 
> General Information   
>  WebTrends Corporation is firmly committed to the privacy of customers and visitors to its web sites. We are equally committed to the privacy of the data we collect for sites using our eService, and the visitors who frequent those sites. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for www.WebTrendsLive.com. Other WebTrends sites may have different policies. 
> 
> Privacy Statement for Visitors to Sites Tracked by WebTrends Live 
> 
> **Privacy Principles**  
>  Because your privacy is important to us, WebTrends Live conducts its business under the following principles: 
> 
> **Principle 1 - No Collection of Personal Information**  
>  WebTrends does not collect personal information such as name, age, phone number and mailing address from visitors to our customer's web sites. 
> 
> **Principle 2 - No Combination of Browsing and Web Traffic Information with Personal Information**  
>  Since WebTrends does not collect any personal information, we do not combine traffic analysis information with personal information such as name, age, phone number and mailing address. 
> 
> **Principle 3 - No Aggregation of Individual Visitor Traffic Patterns across Multiple Sites**  
>  WebTrends does not collect individual profile information for visitors across multiple sites and does not aggregate information from any other sources about browsing patterns of individual visitors across multiple sites. 
> 
> **Principle 4 - Use of Anonymous IP Address**  
>  IP addresses are recorded by every site on the internet. WebTrends collects this information as well, but does so exclusively for the following uses: (1) anonymous statistical purposes; or (2) administration of our web site and servers, and to improve our services. 
> 
> **Principle 5 - Anonymous Use of Cookies**  
>  It is WebTrends Live's policy to use cookies only for more accurate anonymous traffic analysis. The cookie information does NOT include personal data such as name, age, phone number, e-mail address or mailing address. In addition, WebTrends does NOT link cookies to personal data such as name, age, phone number, e-mail address and mailing address. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to reject cookies. 
> 
> **Principle 6 - No Individual Profiling**  
>  WebTrends Live does not create individual profiles for visitors. Unlike other tracking services we do not have a database of individual profiles for each visitor. WebTrends Live collects data in aggregate form and data is not recorded or stored for individual visitors. 
> 
> **Principle 7 - Limited Use of Cookies**  
>  WebTrends Live uses cookies to track such as the time/date of the visit, the time/date of last visit, the page viewed, the referrer, transaction information for eCommerce pages, and other data. The cookies never include personal information such as name, mailing address and phone number. We do not collect such information and visitors that we track can not provide us with personal information through normal movement across a web site. As we do not build a database of individual visitors, the data that we do collect is never stored in any individual user profile; the data collected serves only to update aggregate counts allowing our customers to monitor traffic on their site. Visitors can also reject cookies. 
> 
> **Opting Out of Tracking Cookies**  
>  You may elect to opt out of receiving tracking cookies for all sites using WebTrends Live services. To do so, you will need to accept a cookie indicating your choice. Please visit our **opt out page** for more information. 
> 
> Privacy Statement for Customers Using WebTrends Live to Track their Web Sites
> 
> **Privacy Principles**   
>  Because your privacy is important to us, WebTrends Live conducts its business under the following principles: 
> 
> **Principle 1 - Your Information is Confidential**   
>  All the statistical information we compile for your web site is considered confidential. Statistics about your websites are protected by usernames and passwords; do not disclose these to unauthorized persons. To ensure this privacy, our Data Center is protected by industry standard security technology, such as firewalls and security analyzers using SSL encryption to protect transmission of data. 
> 
> **Principle 2 - WebTrends Has Limited Access to your Information**   
>  WebTrends Corporation will not access, modify, or otherwise divulge the statistical information we compile for your site except for the express purpose of generating reports which have been authorized by you or otherwise agreed to by you, or unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of WebTrends Live; (3) enforce the WebTrends Live Terms of Service; or (4) troubleshoot any service problems. 
> 
> **Principle 3 - No Site-Specific Data is Ever Divulged**  
>  WebTrends Live compiles statistics across all the web sites its services concerning certain broad categories, such as internet browser usage and screen resolution. This information is presented only in an aggregate form, and in no event will we present specific site data without permission. 
> 
> **Principle 4 - Use of Cookies**  
>  Cookies are pieces of information that a web site transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make a web site more useful by personalizing information for visitors and by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and many major web sites use them to provide useful features for their customers. It is WebTrends Live's policy to use cookies only for the following purposes: 
> 
> Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to reject cookies. However, you will not be able to take advantage of our web site if you do so. Your visitors can also reject cookies. If a visitor to your web site rejects cookies, WebTrends Live captures only a subset of the information necessary to generate all traffic reports. 
> 
> WebTrends uses a third party to serve the advertisements that you see on the pages of the WebTrends Live web site. If you would like to know more about the information gathering practices and "opt-out" procedures of our third party ad server, please click [here](http://www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/). 
> 
> **Principle 5 - Personal Information**  
>  Our site's registration form may require users who signed up for our service to give us contact information (such as their name and e-mail address), and financial information (such as their credit card numbers). Personal and financial information that is collected is used to check the user's qualifications for registration and to bill the user for products and services. WebTrends does not store such information linked to a cookie. 
> 
> We may use this information to: 
> 
> Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings. To remove your name from our mailing list, please go to <http://www.webtrendslive.com/remove.asp>. 
> 
> **Privacy Disclosure and Indemnification**  
>  You hereby agree to disclose to your users that you use WebTrends Live to track traffic to your site, and to provide them with a link to our Privacy Policy. You agree to defend, at your expense, any action brought against Developer arising out of your use of the Service with any third parties or from your willful misconduct. You will indemnify Developer from any costs, damages and fees incurred by WebTrends, which are attributable to such a claim. 
> 
> For More Information  
>  If you have any questions or comments about this policy, our services, or your experience with WebTrends Live, you can use the Feedback page on our site, or write to us at: 
> 
> WebTrends Corporation Headquarters  
>  851 SW 6th Avenue  
>  Suite 1200  
>  Portland OR 97204 USA
